const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",t="accounting",o=200,i=120,a=[{id:152,question:"Opening balance of Diksacompany was 12, 202, closing balance N15,300, total cash received during the period N40, 000. What was the amount of cash paid during the same period?",option:{a:"N36. 902",b:"N27,502",c:"N12,498",d:"N43.098"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:183,question:"Accumulated depreciation at the time of sale was",option:{a:"N= 16,000",b:"N=  14,000",c:"N=  12,000",d:"N=  8,000"},section:"An asset was bought on 1st January, 1992 for N= 20,000. Depreciation was provided for annually at 20% on cost. It was sold for N= 7,000 on 1st July, 1995.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:61,question:"To arrive at the gross profit of a trading  business, which one of the following formulate is applied?",option:{a:"Sales - (Opening Stock-Purchases-Closing Stock)",b:"Sales - (Opening stock + Purchases + Closing Stock)",c:"Sales - (Opening stock + Purchases - Closing Stock)",d:"Sales - (Opening stock - purchases + closing stock)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:107,question:"In departmental accounts, administrative expenses are recorded in the",option:{a:"Trading Account.",b:"Balance Sheet.",c:"Profit and Loss Account.",d:"Profit and Loss Appropriation Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:385,question:"Subscriptions in advance is classified in the balance sheet as",option:{a:"an asset",b:"a liability",c:"a deficit",d:"a surplus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:455,question:"A pension granted to any past president or vice-president shall be charged to the",option:{a:"consolidated revenue fund",b:"special pension fund",c:"contingency fund",d:"development fund."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:403,question:"Where closing stock is undervalued, the effect is",option:{a:"an increase in gross profit",b:"a decrease in gross profit",c:"an increase in purchases",d:"a decrease in purchases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:170,question:"The yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be",option:{a:"N5,200",b:"N6,500",c:"N8, 800",d:"N4, 400"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:475,question:"If Mr. Ajasin paid his creditors N 5 000 out of N 20 000 owed, what would be the effect of this transaction on the accounting equation?",option:{a:"A decrease .in the total liabilities and assets by N5 000.",b:"An increase in total liabilities and owners’ equity by N15 000.",c:"An increase in the total assets by N15 000",d:"A decrease in owners’ equity by N 5 000."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:99,question:"Which of the following is determined in the Trading Account?",option:{a:"Factory overheads",b:"Cost of goods sold",c:"Prime cost",d:"Net profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:20,question:"  Prepaid wages is an item in the (i)Balance Sheet (ii) Profit and loss account (iii)Trading  account (iv) Cash account ",option:{a:"i, ii, iii only ",b:"ii, iii  ",c:"i, ii ",d:"iii, iv"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:464,question:"The amount to be charged to the profit and loss account is",option:{a:"N 30,000",b:"N25,000",c:"N 5 ,000",d:"N20,000."},section:"Given: Prepaid b/f [N10, 000 ]; Cash paid during the year  [N20, 000]; Prepaid c/f [N5, 000] ",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:297,question:"Administrative, selling and distribution expenses in a 	manufacturing firm are recorded in",option:{a:"Trading Account.",b:"Manufacturing Account.",c:"Profit and Loss Account.",d:"Balance Sheet."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:213,question:"The art of collecting, recording, presenting and interpreting accounting data is",option:{a:"cost accounting",b:"management accounting",c:"financial accounting",d:"data processing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:127,question:"A trading account is prepared to disclose the",option:{a:"net profit or loss for the year.",b:"gross profit or loss for the year.",c:"accumulated fund for the year.",d:"gross profit on manufacturing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:149,question:"A discount that is allowed to encourage a debtor to pay off his debt within a period is the",option:{a:"trade discount",b:"annual discount",c:"periodic discount",d:"cash discount."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:11,question:"The journal is a book ",option:{a:"of primary entry into which all transactions are entered before posting ",b:"kept by journalist for reporting events ",c:"of prime entry into which postings are made from the ledger  ",d:"of analyzing major accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:461,question:"I.    Facilitating the preparation of final accounts II.   Making the existence of error easy to detect III. Checking the accuracy of postings periodically. From the above, which of the following are among the uses of control accounts?",option:{a:"I, II and III",b:"I and III",c:"II and III",d:"I and II."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:49,question:"Which of the following entries classes the  owner's drawing account at the end of the period?",option:{a:"Debit the drawing account, credit the owner's capital account",b:"Debit the income summary account credit the drawing account",c:"Debit   the   drawing account credit income summary accounting",d:"Debit the owner's capital account, credit the drawing account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:147,question:"Which of the following -is -correct about the imprest system?",option:{a:"II and IV",b:"I, III and IV",c:"I, II and III",d:"III and IV"},section:"I.   The amount of the imprest is the same from one organization to another. II. At the end of a fixed period, the petty cashier received a fixed sum of money.  III.  At the end of a period, the petty-cashier is reimbursed, with the amount spent in that period. IV. The system is a method by which a measure  of control is kept on petty cash expenses",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:204,question:"Which of the following best describes the path of a transaction?",option:{a:"Source documents to Journal to Ledger",b:"Source documents to Ledger to Journal",c:"Journal to Ledger to source documents",d:"Journal to source documents to Ledger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:169,question:"If the scrap value is now N15, 000, what will be the yearly depreciation using straight line method?",option:{a:"N11 000",b:"N7, 000",c:"N 4, 000",d:"N24. 000"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:354,question:"Which of the following is used to record the disposal of a fixed asset?",option:{a:"Journal  Proper",b:"Petty  Cash  Book",c:"Sales Day Book",d:"Purchases Day Book"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:458,question:"Using the straight-line method, the depreciation of the asset in 	the first year was",option:{a:"N  210 m",b:"N 343m",c:"N 105m",d:"N 270m."},section:"An asset was purchased for  N 343 m in 2003. The estimated life of the asset was 3 years with a residual value of  N28 m.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:66,question:"9.   Which   of   the   following   is   a   correct expression of the accounting equation? ",option:{a:"Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity ",b:"Assets = Liabilities - Owner's Equity ",c:"Assets + Owners' Equity = Liabilities ",d:"Assets = Liabilities - Owner's Equity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:284,question:"Which of the following is not found in the personal ledger?",option:{a:"Debtors Account",b:"Creditors Account",c:"Capital Account",d:"Nominal Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:388,question:"A manufacturing account is drawn up by",option:{a:"firms providing personal services",b:"firms engaged solely in buying and selling of goods",c:"firms which make and sell articles",d:"non - trading organization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:322,question:"Which of the following items is found in the sales ledger control account?",option:{a:"Discount received",b:"Total credit purchases",c:"Discount allowed",d:"Returns outwards"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:273,question:"Which of the following is not prepared by a partnership?",option:{a:"Trading Account",b:"Profit and Loss Account",c:"Income and Expenditure Account",d:"Profit and Loss Appropriation Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:188,question:"A financial plan of action expressed in monetary terms is known as",option:{a:"imprest",b:"consolidated fund",c:"warrant",d:"budget"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:419,question:"A rapidly growing business organization with multiple units that is interested in comparing the performances and weaknesses of each unit should adopt.",option:{a:"manufacturing accounts",b:"consolidated accounts",c:"departmental accounts",d:"joint venture accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:29,question:"Accounting equation is given by  ",option:{a:"Assets - Liabilities + Owner's Equity ",b:"Assets = Liabilities - Owner's Equity ",c:"Assets + Owner's Equity = Liabilities ",d:"Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:407,question:"The beginning and ending accounts receivable balances were N 20,000 and N 30,000 respectively.The collection from customers during the period was N 70.000. What was the total sale on account?",option:{a:"N 20,000",b:"N 60,000",c:"N 80,000",d:"N 120,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:219,question:"Books of account consists of",option:{a:"ledgers and subsidiary books",b:"ledgers and principal books",c:"folios and subsidiary books",d:"ledgers and cash book."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:163,question:"An increase in government expenditure within a year is taken care of by means of",option:{a:"virement",b:"financial regulations",c:"supplementary estimate",d:"warrant."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:436,question:"Determine the opening cash balance of the club",option:{a:"N 3070",b:"N 2220",c:"N 5710",d:"N 4320."},section:"Entrance fees [N 1,200 ]; Subscription (including N 850 arrears) [N 4,310 ]; Donations received [N 1,500]; Proceeds from sales [N 2 ,300]; Total payments [N 8,200 ]; Depreciation [N 2,100]; Closing cash balance [N 1,110 ]. The club deposited 200% of the closing cash balance in the bank during the period.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:304,question:"Which of the following is not a feature of accounting information?",option:{a:"Affordability",b:"Timeliness",c:"Accuracy",d:"Completeness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:115,question:"In a not-for-profit making organization, the cash book is referred to as",option:{a:"income and expenditure account.",b:"receipts and payments account.",c:"two column cash book.",d:"petty cash book."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:358,question:"Which of the following is entered in the general journal?",option:{a:"Purchase of goods",b:"Sale of goods on credit",c:"Returns inwards",d:"Acquisition of fixed assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:237,question:"In a system of incomplete records, the opening capital is determined by preparing",option:{a:"statement of affairs",b:"balance sheet",c:"cash book",d:"trial balance."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:193,question:"A real account is the account of",option:{a:"expenses or losses",b:"gains or income",c:"physical tangible items",d:"fictitious items"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:5,question:"Which of the following is a function of the sales journal ",option:{a:"it records both cash and credit sales ",b:"it shows the balance in the sales account ",c:"it record credit sales only ",d:"it shows the aggregate balances in the debtors lodger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:280,question:"The term used to denote the capital of a not-for-profit making 	organization is",option:{a:"annuity fund.",b:"nominal capital.",c:"circulating capital.",d:"cumulated fund"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:241,question:"A set of instructions fed into a computer for accomplishing a given task is a/an",option:{a:"input",b:"programme",c:"output",d:"data."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:393,question:"The loss of equipment in a fire disaster results in",option:{a:"a decrease in current assets",b:"an increase in liabilities and assets",c:"a decrease in assets and capital",d:"an increase in liabilities and a decrease in  assets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:122,question:"Stock account is a type of",option:{a:"nominal account.",b:"personal account.",c:"real account.",d:"fixed assets account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:411,question:"What is the figure for purchases?",option:{a:"N 2,400",b:"N 2,500",c:"N 4,200",d:"N 5,200"},section:"Beginning inventory [ ? ]; Purchases [? ]; Ending inventory [ N4,800 ]; Sales [ N12,800 ]; Wages [ N1,040 ]; Gross profit [N 5,900]. The beginning inventory was estimated at 80% of sales.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:209,question:"The amount of goodwill was",option:{a:"N  4,000",b:"N  3,000",c:"N  2,000",d:"N  1,000."},section:"A business whose assets consisted of stock  N 15,000 and debtors   N  8,000 was bought by issuing 20,000 ordinary shares of   N  1 each at a premium of  20 percent.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:474,question:"The total of the trial balance is",option:{a:"N 6 600",b:"N 6 650",c:"N 5 600",d:"N 5 900"},section:"Given: Returns inwards [N1, 500]; Cash [N1, 550]; Discount received [N2, 850]; Capital [N3, 800 ]; Debtors [N900];	Sundry expenses [  ?  ]; 	The value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:15,question:"Money spent on buying of plots of land by a firm is ",option:{a:"Capital Expenditure ",b:"capital receipts ",c:"Revenue Expenditure",d:" Revenue Receipts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:14,question:"Money set aside for the saving of business overheads    is    referred    to   ",option:{a:"Capital Expenditure  ",b:"Revenue  Expenditure ",c:"Revenue receipts",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:379,question:"An example of input device of a computer is",option:{a:"an optical character reader",b:"a graph plotter",c:"a visual display unit",d:"printer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:106,question:"Which of the following is a recurrent expenditure in public sector accounting?",option:{a:"Purchase of vehicles",b:"Purchase of drugs",c:"Construction of boreholes",d:"Construction of buildings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:468,question:"Journal proper is used in recording",option:{a:"transactions that are not regular",b:"returns from customers",c:"credit sales",d:"the receipt and payment of  money"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following is a spreadsheet application?",option:{a:"Excel",b:"Word",c:"Internet",d:"Windows"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:344,question:"The quality of output information depends on the",option:{a:"quality of input data",b:"time of processing",c:"speed of processing",d:"quantity of output device"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:276,question:"The concept which establishes the rule for the periodic recognition of revenue as soon as it is capable of objective measurement is",option:{a:"going concern.",b:"entity.",c:"consistency.",d:"realization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:310,question:"The accounting ledger for goods sold on credit are debit",option:{a:"Debtors Account, credit Sales Account",b:"Creditors Account, credit Sales Account",c:"Sales Account, credit Debtors Account",d:"Sales Account, credit Creditors Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:378,question:"The primary classification of government expenditure is based on",option:{a:"Programs",b:"funds",c:"activity",d:"project"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:293,question:"Which of the following is not part of the Central Processing Unit of a computer?",option:{a:"Arithmetical and Logical unit",b:"Memory unit",c:"Input unit",d:"Control unit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:179,question:"An example of appropriation of profit in a company is",option:{a:"salaries",b:"rent income",c:"debenture interest",d:"dividend."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:478,question:"The process of bookkeeping includes records produced from",option:{a:"ledgers",b:"source documents",c:"minutes of meeting",d:"intuitive reasoning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:416,question:"In the balance sheet, the subscription in arrears will be",option:{a:"N 200",b:"N 300",c:"N 1,200",d:"N 1,300"},section:"On January 1, 2000, a club’s assets and liabilities were as follows: Club house [ N8,000 ]; Subscription in arrears [ N300]; Cash [N1,000]; Wages owed [N100]. The club has 50 members and annual subscription is N 100 per member. Subscription received is N 4,000 and this includes 1999 arrears of  N 200.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:252,question:"The adjusted cash book balance is",option:{a:"D11,200",b:"D8,400",c:"D6,200",d:"D5,600"},section:"Balance as per cash book [8,400], Bank charges [300], Standing order paid [2,500 ], Unpresented cheques [2,800]",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:129,question:"The records of Superstores shows a loan of  N14,000 from Bala, creditor N8, 000 and assets N190, 500. What is the firm’s capital?",option:{a:"184, 000",b:"1 96, 500",c:"212 000",d:"168, 500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:78,question:"  Which of the following is not part of the main uses of the journal ",option:{a:" purchase and sale   of   fixed   assets   on  credit   ",b:"the  correction of errors ",c:"writing off bad debts ",d:"none of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:235,question:"“A business unit is assumed to operate into foreseeable future and earn reasonable net income”. This statement is emphasized by the concept of",option:{a:"business entity",b:"going concern",c:"realization",d:"accrual."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:77,question:"Which of the following is a fictitious asset? ",option:{a:"prepayments ",b:"preliminary expenses ",c:"investment ",d:"plant and machinery "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:138,question:"Which of the following conditions would attract credit and debit notes to be used?",option:{a:"When goods are received from supplier.",b:"When a trial balance is extracted",c:"When a buyer is under or over charged.",d:"When goods are sold to a buyer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:394,question:"A source document is used for verifying the",option:{a:"amount due to creditors",b:"actual cost of an asset",c:"selling price of goods",d:"amount due from debtors"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:251,question:"Which of the following columns of a three column cash book 	are memoranda?  I. Discount received  II. Discount allowed III. Cash IV. Bank",option:{a:"I and II only",b:"I and III only",c:"II and III only",d:"ll and IV only."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:48,question:"If goods purchased on account is returned, the buyer may inform the seller of the details by issuing:",option:{a:"An invoice  ",b:"A debt memorandum",c:"A credit memorandum  ",d:" A bill"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:239,question:"Prime cost is",option:{a:"D120,500",b:"D117,700",c:"D114,900",d:"D114,300."},section:"Given Opening stock:  raw materials [10,000 ], work-in-progress [16,000],  Purchases of raw materials [95,500] , Direct labour wages paid [13,500], Royalties paid [6,200], Accrued wages[2,800], Closing stock- raw materials [7,500], work-in-progress[ 8,500], 	Manufacturing overhead [10,000]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:205,question:"Where there are no proper books of account, the capital at the commencement of a period is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"Total Debtors and Creditors Accounts",b:"Bank Reconciliation Statement",c:"Statement of Affairs",d:"Trading, Profit and Loss Accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:43,question:"Which of the following would not be included in a balance sheet?",option:{a:"Accounts receivable",b:"Accounts payable  ",c:"Sales",d:"Cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:151,question:"The impersonal account is subdivided into",option:{a:"realand nominal accounts",b:"nominal and personal accounts",c:"real and current accounts",d:"personal and real accounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:342,question:"Which of the following is found on the credit side of a partnership’s appropriation of profit account?",option:{a:"Interest on capital",b:"Interest on drawings",c:"share of profit",d:"Drawings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:372,question:"Which of the following items is not contained in the Receipts and Payments Account?",option:{a:"Subscription paid in advance",b:"tock paid for in advance",c:"Outstanding wages and salaries",d:"Donations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:103,question:"The accounting principle that states that, in the preparation of accounting statement, revenue are recognized as        soon as goods are passed on to the customer is the",option:{a:"materiality concept.",b:"matching concept.",c:"consistency concept.",d:"realization concept."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:330,question:"Goodwill is recognized in partnership accounts when",option:{a:"the business makes a huge profit",b:"the business has good customer relationship",c:"a partner is dormant",d:"a new partner is admitted"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:180,question:"In a partnership goodwill is recognized when",option:{a:"a new partner is admitted",b:"a partner is dormant",c:"the business is making huge profit",d:"the business has good customer relations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:473,question:"How much is sundry expenses?",option:{a:"N 2 700",b:"N 2,250",c:"N1,550",d:"N2000."},section:"Given: Returns inwards [N1, 500]; Cash [N1, 550]; Discount received [N2, 850]; Capital [N3, 800 ]; Debtors [N900];	Sundry expenses [  ?  ]; 	The value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:406,question:"In a sales ledger, contra entry is found on the",option:{a:"debit side of the debtors’ control account",b:"debit side of the creditors’ control account",c:"credit side of the debtors’ control account",d:"credit side of the creditors’ control account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:28,question:"Errors   revealed   by   the   trial   balance include error of:  ",option:{a:"Principle  ",b:"Single entry ",c:"Omission  ",d:"commission "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:427,question:"The accounting entry to record the premium on goodwill is to debit",option:{a:"cash and credit old partners’ capital",b:"goodwill and credit revaluation",c:"assets and credit capital",d:"capital and credit assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:36,question:"Which   accounting  concept  states; that revenues and expenses are recognized as they are earned or incurred and not when  money is received?",option:{a:"Entity   ",b:"Realization",c:"Accrual  ",d:"Periodicity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:295,question:"An underwriter for a company’s share is paid",option:{a:"Interest.",b:"commission.",c:"dividend.",d:"salary."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:65,question:"MORADE had total assets of N760,000, capital stock of N150,000 and retained earnings of N215,000. What was Morade's debt-to-equity ratio? ",option:{a:"2.63",b:"1.08",c:"0.52",d:"0.48"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:225,question:"The dividend per ordinary share for the year is",option:{a:"N  0.88 kobo",b:"N  0.40 kobo",c:"N  0.20 kobo",d:"N  0.17 kobo"},section:"Ordinary shares of  N1each  [500,000], 8% preference shares of  N1each [200,000], Interim dividends paid:  - ordinary shares [40,000], - preference shares [12,000], Profit for the year [100,000]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:383,question:"Calculate the stock figure to be included in the balance sheet at the year end.",option:{a:"D408,000",b:"D346,000",c:"D284,000",d:"D62,000"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:220,question:"The amount set aside out of profits earned by a company which are not meant for liability or contingency are",option:{a:"dividends",b:"provisions",c:"retained profits",d:"reserves"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:133,question:"The instrument used in analysis and interpretation of financial statement is the",option:{a:"accounting ratios",b:"income and expenditure extract",c:"balance sheet extract",d:"fund accounting."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:16,question:"Prepaid expenses  is an  item  in ",option:{a:"Fixed Asset  ",b:"  Current    Asset   ",c:"Liabilities ",d:"Long term liabilities "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:105,question:"A low current ratio in a business indicates that the business is",option:{a:"faced with long term loan repayment problem.",b:"efficient in the utilization of its resources.",c:"unable to pay its bills on time.",d:"growing its net asset effectively."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:286,question:"Capital expenditure for the year was",option:{a:"Le 545,000",b:"Le 490,000",c:"Le 450,000",d:"Le 300,000"},section:"The Health Department of Zango Local Government incurred the following expenditure in 2010. Construction of hospital wards [ Le 300,000 ]; Purchase of hospital beds [ Le  40,000 ]; Salaries and wages  [ Le 80,000]; Purchase of drugs  [ Le 55,000]; Purchase of X-ray machine [ Le 150,000]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:72,question:"A business shows total debtors' balance of N400,000 in its ledger at the end of its financial customer owing N40,00 are bankrupt, and there is no  possibility of getting the debt paid. A further 2% of the debt is considered doubtful. What debtor’ total will be included as a current asset in the balance sheet? ",option:{a:"N400,000  ",b:"N352,800  ",c:"N352, 000  ",d:"N36, 200"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:380,question:"The accounting concept which states that expenditure involving insignificant amounts should be regarded as expenses and not assets is",option:{a:"business entity",b:"materiality",c:"dual aspect",d:"realization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:143,question:"Badge Plc issued 450, 000 ordinary shares, of 50K each at N1 .50 per share. Application and allotment 45k, 1st call 50k, 2nd call 55k. Determine the amount received on final call.",option:{a:"N225, 000",b:"N236, 250",c:"N 247, 500",d:"N 202, 500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:191,question:"The double entry required for the mark-up is debit Branch",option:{a:"Sales Account, credit Branch Adjustment Account",b:"Adjustment Account, credit Branch Stock Account",c:"Stock Account, credit Branch Adjustment Account",d:"Profit and Loss Account, credit Branch Stock Account,"},section:"A company charges out goods to a branch at cost plus 25 percent.  It invoiced  N 12,000 worth of goods",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:59,question:"If a business pays for only 11 months rent during a financial year, what accounting term is given to the outstanding term is given to the outstanding one month's rent? Which of the following equations properly represents a derivation of the fundamental accounting equation?",option:{a:"Assets + liabilities = owner's equity ",b:"Assets = owner's equity",c:"Cash = assets.  ",d:"Assets - liabilities = owner's equity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:340,question:"The instrument used to release fund which the minister of finance had earlier withheld is",option:{a:"reserve expenditure warrant",b:"supplementary general warrant",c:"provisional general warrant",d:"supplementary statutory warrant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:112,question:"When a business is purchased from a sole trader, the excess of the purchase price over the net assets is",option:{a:"reserve.",b:"goodwill.",c:"freehold.",d:"valuation price."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:491,question:"Using FIFO method, what is the value of the closing stock?",option:{a:"N 34,000",b:"N 29,000",c:"N 17,000",d:"N 12,000"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Jan. 1 Received 1,000 units at   N 10 each; Jan. 2 Received 2,000 units at   N  12 each; Jan. 3 Issued 1,500 units; Jan. 4 Received 1,000 units at   N  11 eac; Jan. 5 Issued 1000 units",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:256,question:"Rent expenses for the year 2005 is",option:{a:"N 11,400",b:"N  11,300",c:"N  11,200",d:"N  10,200."},section:"Rent accrued 1st January, 2005 [600], Rent paid in 2005 [11,300], Rent prepaid 31st December, 2005 [500]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:489,question:"What is the net working capital?",option:{a:"N 2,600",b:"N1,800",c:"N 800",d:"N 600"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Total current assets [N2,000 ]; Total fixed assets [N 4,000 ]; Current liabilities [N 1,200 ]; Drawings [N 200 ]; Long-term loan 	[N 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:421,question:"Discounts granted to branch customers are treated as a debit to branch",option:{a:"stock account and a credit to branch debtors’ account",b:"discount account and a credit to branch bank account",c:"stock account and a credit to branch bank account",d:"discount account and a credit to branch debtors’ account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:190,question:"The mark-up is",option:{a:"N  15,000",b:"N 9,000",c:"N  4,000",d:"N  3,000"},section:"A company charges out goods to a branch at cost plus 25 percent.  It invoiced  N 12,000 worth of goods",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:418,question:"In the balance sheet of a not-for-profit-making organization, subscription paid in advance is regarded as a",option:{a:"current asset",b:"current liability",c:"capital",d:"reserve"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:268,question:"Capital receipt is collected",option:{a:"on sales of motor vehicle.",b:"on sales of stock in trade.",c:"from trade debtor",d:"from trading activities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:501,question:"What is the accumulated fund?",option:{a:"23,700",b:"27,750",c:"29,650",d:"51,650"},section:"Given: Furniture and fittings [N 20,000]  Equipment [N15,000] Bank overdrafts [ N6,500] Bar creditors [ N4,800 ] Subscription in arrears [ N4,700 ] Subscription in advance [ N650]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:46,question:"If the equipment account has a balance of N22.500 and its accumulated account has a balance of N14,000 the book value of the equipment is:  ",option:{a:"N22.500   ",b:"N8.500 ",c:"N 14,000  ",d:"N36.500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:41,question:'Wilson Company owns land which cost 14100, 000. If a "quick sate" of the land was necessary to generate cash, the company feels it would receive only N80, 000.    The company continues to report the asset on the balance sheet at N100, 000   This is justified under which of the following concepts?  ',option:{a:"The historical-cost principle.",b:"The value is tied to objective and verifiable past transactions.",c:"Neither of the above.",d:' Both "a" and "b"'},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:431,question:"According to the provisions of the 1999 Constitution, all revenues generated by the Federal Government must be paid into the?",option:{a:"Consolidated Revenue Fund",b:"Federation Account",c:"Revenue Mobilization Allocation and Fiscal Commission’s Account",d:"Equalization Fund"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:253,question:"The balance as per bank statement is",option:{a:"D10,900",b:"D8,400",c:"D5,600",d:"D2,800"},section:"Balance as per cash book [8,400], Bank charges [300], Standing order paid [2,500 ], Unpresented cheques [2,800]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:370,question:"In a not - for - profit making organization, when the total income 	is less than the total expenditure, the difference is a",option:{a:"surplus",b:"shortfall",c:"loss",d:"deficit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:368,question:"When an asset is sold, the entries for the accumulated depreciation are: debit",option:{a:"Asset Disposal Account; credit Provision for Depreciation Account.",b:"Provision for Depreciation Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",c:"Fixed Asset Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",d:"Asset Disposal Account; Credit Fixed Asset Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:327,question:"The accounting concept that allows the cost of kitchen cutlery to be expensed, though it will be used for more than one year is",option:{a:"materiality",b:"accrual",c:"going concern",d:"business entity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:345,question:"The source document used to make entries in the purchases day book is",option:{a:"debit note",b:"credit note",c:"invoice",d:"receipt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:202,question:"The person, who is responsible for the formation of a company is called the",option:{a:"promoter",b:"sponsor",c:"shareholder",d:"director"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:131,question:"One of the objectives of accounting is that it can be used for",option:{a:"business decision making",b:"due process in business",c:"motivating employees",d:"determining the work force."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"}],n={message:e,subject:t,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,t as subject,i as total};
